<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Blog That Works on Arun Mitra</title>
    <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Blog That Works on Arun Mitra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arunmitra.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Non-Communicable Diseases &amp; Ayurveda</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2022-04-20-ncd-ayurveda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2022-04-20-ncd-ayurveda/</guid>
      <description>The blog is a write-up on a talk I have given at the Institute of Management in Government, Thiruvanthapuram, Kerala on 19th April, 2022. It was presented at the training of the state Auryvedic Medical Officers (STP 608) in Kerala on Non Communicable Diseases. STP608 is a course developed by the Indian System of Medicine (ISM), Government of Kerala for training the state medical officers in Ayurveda. Head over to the talk page https://arunmitra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World! - My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2022-04-16-hello-world-my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2022-04-16-hello-world-my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Little over an year ago I decided to build a personal web space where I can document, archive &amp;amp; organise my work, and possibly share it with others. Since I have no formal training anything remotely related to IT or web development, it proved to be quite a bit of a challenge.
There are three steps in my approach. I am going to briefly describe them on the following blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Epidemic in India</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-epidemic-curve-of-covid-19-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-epidemic-curve-of-covid-19-in-india/</guid>
      <description>The importance of epidemic curves in epidemiology in understanding and visualising the onset and progression of an epidemic is immense. It provides key insights in terms of the magnitude of the disease, the mode of transmission, trends over time and the incubation period.
The below interactive plot is variant of the epidemic curve of COVID-19 in India. By default, the weekly average of daily cases, recovered and deaths is presented in the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Effective Reproduction Number for the COVID-19 Epidemic in India</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-estimating-effective-reproduction-number-for-the-covid-19-epidemic-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-estimating-effective-reproduction-number-for-the-covid-19-epidemic-in-india/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Wave vs Second Wave</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-first-wave-vs-second-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-first-wave-vs-second-wave/</guid>
      <description>The abrupt onset of the second wave of COVID-19 in India has taken the country by storm. With over 4,00,000 cases being reported daily, India has over 37,00,000 active cases as of 12, May 2021. This post aims to estimate the epidemiological parameters of COVID-19 epidemic in India during the first and second waves.
As discussed in the previous post, India’s epidemic curve suggests an ongoing second wave of COVID-19 infections in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Inequities in COVID-19 Vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-gender-inequities-in-covid-19-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/2021-05-12-gender-inequities-in-covid-19-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>This post looks into the COVID-19 vaccinations in India and the respective states. The data is downloaded from COVID-19 India Tracker Website as provided in the data sources section in the methodology.
Total Vaccinations## Warning in RColorBrewer::brewer.pal(N, &amp;quot;Set2&amp;quot;): n too large, allowed maximum for palette Set2 is 8## Returning the palette you asked for with that many colors## Warning in RColorBrewer::brewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up your social</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>There are five places where you can choose to show social icons. Here is the tl;dr:
 site header (set in config.toml), site footer (set in config.toml),  homepage (set in content/_index.md),  about page in the sidebar (set in content/about/sidebar/index.md), and  contact page (set in content/form/contact.md).  Read on to learn how to set up your social icons, and how to show/hide them.
Configure social     Wherever you end up wanting to show your social icons, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to start by setting up the links in your site config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site colors</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>You can totally customize your site&amp;rsquo;s theme colors within minutes of creating a new site. Read on to find out how, and decide which of the three options meets your needs.
Use a color theme     Hugo Apéro includes 8 built-in color themes that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; This means you can use a color theme to quickly customize the look of your site without needing to write any CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site typography</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>As with color themes, you can completely customize your site&amp;rsquo;s fonts within minutes of creating a new site. How you do it depends on how much control and customization you need.
Embedded fonts     Hugo Apéro includes 6 embedded fonts that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; We selected 3 serif and 3 sans-serif options that we thought looked good with this theme, in our humble opinions. All embedded fonts include real italics so you may emphasize to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content ❤️!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evergreen post</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/evergreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/evergreen/</guid>
      <description>Rendering mathematical equations     Examples from the mathjax demo. But they work with katex as well.
Rmarkdown     In .Rmarkdown documents, you can use either
$a \ne 0$ to get inline math: \(a \ne 0\). There is no conflict with using dollar symbols regularly, because knitr automatically escapes freestanding dollar symbols.
And you can use
$x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}.$$ to get a math paragraph:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset
For example, this panelset:
Hello! 👋 hello
 Goodbye 💨 goodbye
  Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:
{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Rmarkdown post</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description> Air quality     with(airquality, boxplot(Temp ~ Month)) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp)) mlev &amp;lt;- levels(with(airquality, as.factor(Month))) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp, pch = as.numeric(mlev), col = mlev)) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Overview     Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Contact Form</title>
      <link>https://arunmitra.com/blog/built-in-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arunmitra.com/blog/built-in-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
